Welcome. In the last lecture, we adjusted two animations for hopping, and in this lecture,
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们调整了两个跳跃的动画，在这节课中，
we'll look at how we can achieve hopping up. So I'm going to close my project first.
我们将看看如何实现跳跃。所以我要先结束我的项目。
Go back to Visual Studio. I'm going to go back to the header file of this custom movement
返回到Visual Studio。我将返回到这个定制移动的头文件
component. Then inside of this Climb Core, I'm going to scroll down. Below, this is
组件。然后在这个攀登核心里面，我要向下滚动。下面，这是
setMotionWarpTarget. I'm going to create two new functions. So the first one is going to
SetMotionWarpTarget。我将创建两个新函数。所以第一个将会是
be void. I'm going to call it handleHopUp. And the second one is going to return a bool.
是空虚的。我要把它叫做HandleHopUp。第二个函数将返回一个bool。
I'm going to call it checkCanHopUp. Alright, I'm going to create two function definitions.
我要将其称为CheckCanHopUp。好的，我将创建两个函数定义。
So paste the function below this setMotionWarpTarget. Place it in here. Create a function definition
因此，将该函数粘贴到此setMotionWarpTarget下面。把它放在这里。创建函数定义
for this checkCanHopUp and place it in here. So first thing, I'm going to call the function
对于这张支票，可以跳起来，把它放在这里。所以第一件事，我要调用函数
handleHopUp inside of this if check. So if our dot result is greater than .9f, I'm going
HANDLEHOP UP在这里面，如果选中。因此，如果我们的点结果大于0.9f，我将
to call the function handleHopUp. Then scroll down inside of this function. So if this check
调用函数handleHopUp。然后在此函数中向下滚动。所以如果这张支票
canHopUp is true, then we should play the montage in here. And the key thing is how
如果是真的，那么我们应该在这里玩蒙太奇。关键是如何
should we implement this checking? Well, actually, we have all these key functions ready. And
我们应该实施这项检查吗？嗯，实际上，我们已经准备好了所有这些关键功能。和
for that, I'm going to use our existing function. So the function is called traceFromIheight.
为此，我将使用我们现有的函数。因此，该函数被称为traceFromIHeight。
And there are two input parameters, the traceDistance and traceStartOffset. And since I also want
有两个输入参数，分别是traceDistance和traceStartOffset。既然我也想
to see the debug shapes, I'm going to modify this function a little bit. So go back to
要查看调试形状，我将对此函数稍作修改。因此，请回到
the header file. I'm going to scroll up to this traceFromIheight. And I'm going to add
头文件。我要滚动到这个高度的轨迹。我还要补充一句
in two new input parameters. So I'm going to expand this ClimbTraces. And I'm going
两个新的输入参数中。因此，我将扩展这一气候轨迹。我要走了
to copy these two input parameters. And I'm going to paste them to this function. And
复制这两个输入参数。我要把它们粘贴到这个函数中。和
I also need to modify the CPP file. So it will be this traceFromIheight. I'm going
我还需要修改CPP文件。所以它将是这个高度的痕迹。我要走了
to paste those two input parameters in here. And add a bool in front of this. Delete this
将这两个输入参数粘贴到这里。在这个前面加一个布尔。删除此内容
false. We don't need this. Delete this one. And now with these two new variables, we can
假的。我们不需要这个。删除这一条。现在有了这两个新的变量，我们可以
enable debug shape per traceFromIheight. So paste the first one in here. Then I'm also
启用每个跟踪的调试形状FromIHeight。因此，将第一个粘贴到这里。那我也是
going to copy the second one. Paste it in here. All right, I'm going to go back to my
我要复制第二个。把它贴在这里。好了，我要回到我的
check and hop up. I'm going to comment on this function first. Then I'm going to try
检查一下，然后跳上来。我将首先对此函数进行评论。那我要试一试
to compile. And I don't have a successful compile, so I'm going to double click this
去汇编。我没有成功的编译，所以我要双击这个
error. So my bool was added to this parameter. I'm going to delete it. And this time it should
错误。所以我的bool加到了这个参数中。我要把它删除。这一次，它应该
work. I'm going to try to compile again. So now the error is gone. And here it says this
工作。我要试着重新编译。所以现在这个错误已经消失了。这里是这样写的
function must return a value. So I'm going to return false for now. And try to compile
函数必须返回值。所以现在我将返回FALSE。并试着编译
again. All right, this time I have a successful compile. And now I'm going to call the function
再来一次。好了，这一次我有一个成功的编译。现在我要调用该函数
traceFromIheight. So the trace distance, I'm going to give it a hard code value of 100
从高度追踪。所以轨迹距离，我将给它一个硬编码值100
units. And now the trace start offset, I'm going to give it a value of -30.f. So by default,
单位。现在轨迹开始偏移量，我会给它一个-30.f的值。因此，默认情况下，
the trace will start from the character's eye height. I'm going to offset it down to
轨迹将从角色的眼睛高度开始。我要把它补偿到
the height of our chest. And I'm also going to pass in true for showing debug shapes.
我们胸口的高度。我还将传递True，以显示调试形状。
All right, I'm going to store the return result of this function inside of an F head result.
好的，我要把这个函数的返回结果存储在F头结果中。
I'm going to call it hopUpHead. And later I'm going to use the impact point as the target
我要把它叫做HopUpHead。稍后，我将使用撞击点作为目标
point for our motion working. I'm also going to perform the second line trace in here.
为我们的动议起作用的要点。我还将在这里执行第二行跟踪。
And for the second one, I'm going to change this start offset to 150.f. And I'm going
对于第二个，我将把这个起始偏移量更改为150.f。我要走了
to call this F head result safetyLedgeHit. So the second line trace here is for us to
将此F Head结果称为SafetyLedgeHit。所以这里的第二行轨迹是我们要做的
detect the ledge. If our character is too close to the ledge, then we shouldn't be able
找出悬崖的位置。如果我们的角色太接近悬崖，那么我们应该不能
to hop up. All right, I'm going to run an if check. So if this hopUpHead.b blocking
跳上来。好的，我要做个假设检查。所以如果这个HopUpHead.b阻塞
head is true and this safetyLedgeHit.b blocking head is true, then I'm going to return true
Head为True且此SafetyLedgeHit.b阻止Head为True，则我将返回True
in this function. Otherwise, I'm just going to return false. All right, inside of this
在这个函数中。否则，我只会返回FALSE。好的，在这里面
handle hopUp, I'm going to print a debug message for now. And the message is going to be can
处理HopUp，我现在要打印一条调试消息。我们要传达的信息是
hop up. And if this condition is false, I'm going to say unable to hop up. All right,
跳起来。如果这个条件是假的，我会说不能跳起来。好的,
one last thing. I'm going to call this function inside of tick just to visualize those debug
最后一件事。我将在Tick内部调用此函数，以可视化这些调试
lines. And that's pretty much it. I'm going to compile. I have a successful compile. I'm
台词。差不多就是这样。我要去汇编一下。我有一个成功的汇编。我
going to launch my editor back. Go back to the editor. I'm going to test this. So click
我要让我的编辑回来。回到编辑那里。我要测试一下这个。因此请点击
play and go to the surface here. I'm going to press F. And you can see this is my first
在这里打球，到地面上去。我要按下F键，你可以看到这是我第一次
line trace. And I'm going to try to move up. And above our character, that's the second
线迹。我要试着往上爬。在我们的角色之上，这是第二个
line trace to detect the ledge. All right, I'm going to move down a bit, then try to
用于检测壁架的线迹。好的，我要往下移一点，然后试着
move up, then press spacebar. It says can hop up. And now I'm going to do it again.
向上移动，然后按空格键。上面写着可以跳起来。现在我要再来一次。
It says unable to hop up. I'm going to try again. Can hop up and unable to hop up. All
上面写着不能跳起来。我要再试一次。可以跳起来，但不能跳起来。全
right. All I have to do is to play the montage. So I'm going to exit the play mode. And I'm
正确的。我所要做的就是播放蒙太奇。所以我要退出播放模式。而且我是
going to select this hop up, CR linked, right mouse button clicked and create an animated
要选择这一跳，点击CR链接，点击鼠标右键并创建动画
montage. I'm going to name this to am_hopup and move it to the montages folder. Select
蒙太奇。我打算将其命名为am_Hopup，并将其移动到montages文件夹。选择
move here. Then double click to open it. And I'm going to add in motion morphing for this
搬到这里来。然后双击将其打开。我将为这个添加运动变形
animation. So right mouse button clicked. Add notify state, motion morphing. And I'm
动画。所以点击了鼠标右键。添加通知状态、运动变形。而且我是
going to scroll to when our character starts moving. So somewhere near here, I think. Move
当我们的角色开始移动时滚动到。所以我想，在这附近的某个地方。移动
it to here. Then increase the length of it. Then I'm going to go to. So somewhere near
它到了这里。然后增加它的长度。然后我要去。所以在附近的某个地方
here. And for this motion morphing setting, it's warp target name. I'm going to change
这里。对于此运动变形设置，它是扭曲目标名称。我要换衣服了
it to hop up target point. And I'm going to untick this ignore z axis and change this
它要跳上目标点.我要取消勾选这个忽略z轴并更改它
easing func to cubic. And also I'm going to increase this blend time for blend in and
放松函数到立方。此外，我还将增加混合时间，以进行混合
blend out. So increase them to 0.3. Change the blend option to cubic and do the same
混在一起。因此，将它们增加到0.3。将混合选项更改为立方体，然后执行相同操作
thing to blend out and change it to cubic as well. All right. Hit save. That's the
混合出来的东西，并将其更改为立方体。好的。点击保存。这就是
montage done. And the last thing we need to take care of the coding part. So close my
蒙太奇完成了。我们需要做的最后一件事是编码部分。所以闭上我的
project again. I'm going to go back to the header file of this movement component. Go
再来一次。我将返回到这个移动组件的头文件。去
inside of this BP variable. Now I'm going to copy this end of montage. Paste it in here.
在此BP变量内部。现在我要复制蒙太奇的这一端。把它贴在这里。
I'm going to call this one hopup montage. And next thing, same as our vaulting, I'm
我要把这一幕叫做跳跃蒙太奇。接下来，和我们的跳马一样，我
going to modify our check and hopup a little bit. So I'm going to give it an out parameter.
我要修改一下我们的支票，稍微提高一下。所以我要给它一个out参数。
And I'm going to call this parameter out hopup target position and modify the cpp file as
我将把这个参数调出Hopup目标位置，并将cpp文件修改为
well. So go to the bottom of my cpp file. Paste this out parameter in here. And if we
井。所以请转到我的CPP文件的底部。将此输出参数粘贴到此处。如果我们
are inside of this if check, I'm going to copy this parameter, paste it in here, and
如果选中，我将复制这个参数，粘贴到这里，然后
it's going to equal to this hopup hit dot impact point. And I'm going to pass in another true.
它等于这个跳跃命中点的落点。我将传递另一个真实的信息。
So we can see the persistent debug line and go back to take. I'm going to remove this
因此，我们可以看到持久调试行，然后返回Take。我要把这个去掉
function in here. Then go back to this handle hop. I'm going to create an F vector in here.
在这里发挥作用。然后回到这个把手跳。我将在这里创建一个F向量。
And I'm going to call it hopup target point and pass this variable into this function.
我将它命名为Hopup Target Point，并将这个变量传递给这个函数。
I'm going to delete this debug function, delete this else case. So if the condition returns
我要删除这个调试函数，删除这个大小写。因此，如果条件再次出现
true, I'm going to call the function set motion warp target. And the target name is going
真的，我将把函数SET称为运动扭曲目标。目标名称将会是
to be this hopup target point. So copy it, paste it in here. And the target location
成为这个跳跃的靶点。所以把它复制，粘贴到这里。和目标位置
is going to be this one. Then after that, I'm going to play client montage, then pass
将会是这一个。然后，我要玩客户蒙太奇，然后通过
in this hopup montage. And that's pretty much it. I'm going to try to compile first.
在这个跳跃的蒙太奇中。差不多就是这样。我要先试着编译。
I have a successful compile. I'm going to launch my editor back. Go back to the editor,
我有一个成功的汇编。我要让我的编辑回来。回到编辑那里，
go inside the client system, double click to open this client character and go to this
进入客户端系统，双击打开此客户端角色，然后转到此
custom moving component. I'm going to assign the montage in here. So it's this AM underscore
自定义移动组件。我要把蒙太奇画在这里。所以是这个AM下划线
hopup and click compile. All right, let's test this. I'm going to click play. Go to
跳起来，然后单击编译。好了，让我们测试一下这个。我要点击播放。去
the surface, move up, press spacebar. And you can see it's working. I'm going to try
表面，向上移动，按空格键。你可以看到它在起作用。我要试一试
again. And this looks great. I'm going to move down a bit, then try to hop up. So I
再来一次。这个看起来很棒。我要往下走一点，然后试着跳上去。所以我
think currently the transition between the locomotion and this hopup montage is not very
我觉得现在移动和这个跳跃蒙太奇之间的过渡不是很好
smooth. So to fix that, we can keep increasing the blend out time for this montage. Right
很顺滑。因此，为了解决这个问题，我们可以继续增加蒙太奇的混合时间。正确的
now it's 0.3. I'm going to try to increase it to 0.4 and try again. So click play and
现在是0.3。我将尝试将其增加到0.4，然后再试一次。因此，请单击播放并
climb up. Yeah, I think it gets a bit better. And we can also climb up to the top and we
爬上去。是啊，我觉得会好一点的。我们也可以爬到山顶，我们
can climb down. So move down a bit, then try again. And I also noticed that while I'm hopping
可以往下爬。所以往下移一点，然后再试一次。我还注意到，当我在跳的时候
up, there's some weird rotation happening. And that's because for my motion warping,
向上，有一些奇怪的轮换发生。这是因为对于我的运动扭曲，
I forgot to untake this warped rotation. So make sure you double check these settings
我忘了取消这个扭曲的旋转。所以一定要仔细检查这些设置
and hit save. Try again. So click play and climb up. And you can see this time it gets
然后点击保存。再试试。因此，点击播放并向上攀登。你可以看到这一次它变得
much better. All right, something like that. I think I quite like the current result. And
好多了。好吧，差不多吧。我想我很喜欢目前的结果。和
when we are near the ledge, you can see because the second line trace does not have a valid
当我们靠近壁架时，您可以看到，因为第二行轨迹没有有效的
hit, we cannot start hopping up. And that's exactly what we want. Great. I think everything
击中，我们就不能开始跳起来了。这正是我们想要的。太棒了。我觉得每件事
is working as expected. And it's time for a challenge. So our challenge is to set up
正在发挥预期的作用。现在是挑战的时候了。因此，我们面临的挑战是建立
the condition check for hopping up. So in here I used the function that we created trace
跳跃的状态检查。在这里，我使用了我们创建的跟踪函数
from iHeight to do that. If that's not what you want, you can set up new line trace functions
从iHeight开始这样做。如果这不是您想要的，您可以设置新的行跟踪函数
to help you to do that. Basically in here you need to rule out this situation when our
来帮助你做到这一点。基本上在这里你需要排除这种情况，当我们的
character is too close to the ledge. Once you have this condition check ready, all that's
角色太接近悬崖了。一旦你准备好了这个条件检查，一切就完成了
left there to do is to use motion warping to set the target location for hopping up.
剩下要做的就是使用运动扭曲来设置跳跃的目标位置。
Make sure you double check the settings for motion warping and feel free to refer back
请确保仔细检查运动扭曲的设置，并随时参考
to the video if you need help. All right, pause the video now and give this a go and
如果你需要帮助的话。好了，现在暂停视频，试一试
I'll see you in the next lecture.
我将在下一节课上见到你。
[music]
[音乐]